Total Experience: 2 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Notice Period: 1 Month

Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Electronics/Telecommunication]

Rajan Sharma () Featured

Two years of experience as a Backend Java Developer with strong Problem Solving, Analytical & Debugging skills. Good at Algorithms & Data Structures. Seeking roles in Software Engineering, Software Development Engineer, Web Development.



Current Designation: Programmer Analyst

Current Company: Cognizant

Current Location: Hyderabad / Secunderabad

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Hyderabad, Pune

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Data Structures, Algorithms, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Web Services, Java, Spring

Boot, Hibernate, MySQL, GIT, System Design, Design Patterns, Maven, Problem Solving, Analytics, Debugging, Software

Development, Application Programming, Software Engineering, Spring, MVC

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 20-Jan-21 Last Modified: 20-Jan-21

Summary

Two years of experience in the industry as a Backend Java Developer with strong Problem Solving, Analytical & Debugging skills. Good at Algorithms & Data Structures. Seeking roles in Software Engineering, Software Development Engineer, Web Development.

Work Experience

Cognizant as Programmer Analyst

Jan 2019 to Till Date

FRM Management and Indexing Services - Travelers

- *Mostly worked on the backend where I created the respective Java objects for the constraints received from inputs and mapped the data to the database in an organized manner for better read/write operations.
- *Designed and maintained a system for efficient storage (and retrieval) of specific file types from directories & subdirectories into the server.
- *Developed a few .jar utility tools that automated some tasks and helped reduce lots of manual work.
- *Technologies: Java, Spring Boot, Hibernate, HTML, CSS, JS, REST API

Freelancer as WordPress Web Developer Oct 2017 to Nov 2018

- * Developed various WordPress websites including dynamic, static, E-commerce, property, etc.
- * Fiverr.com, Freelancer.com, blogs and Google Ads were used for marketing the services offered.

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electronics/Telecommunication) from Malla Reddy Engineering College, Ranga Reddy in 2017

1/22/2021

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

Application Security Testing Data Structures & Algorithms!

Java (Basic)

Azure Fundamentals

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
MySQL, Linux, HTML, CSS, Git,			2 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
Eclipse, Maven, Visual studio		0	2 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
JavaScript, WordPress, SEO			2 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
Data Structures & Algorithms,		0	2 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Proficient			
Hindi	Proficient			
Telugu	Proficient			

Projects

Project Title: FRM Management and Indexing Services

Client: Travelers Companies Nature of Employment: Full Time

Duration: Jul 2019 - Till Date Onsite / Offsite: Offsite Project Location: Chennai

Project Details: FRM Management and Indexing Services Travelers

Mostly worked on the backend where I created the respective Java objects for the constraints received from inputs and mapped the data to the database in an organized way for better read/write operations.

Developed a few .jar utility tools that automated some tasks and helped reduce lots of manual work.

Designed and maintained a system for efficient storage (and retrieval) of specific file types from directories & subdirectories

into the server.

Technologies: Java, Spring Boot, Hibernate, HTML, CSS, JS, REST API

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Category: OBC - non-creamy

Job Type: Permanent

Physically Challenged: No

Employment Status: Full Time, Part Time